oneyoungworld.com 2018-05-24

# Privacy Policy | One Young World

##  Relevant legislation

Along with our business and internal computer systems, this website is designed to comply with the following national and international legislation with regards to data protection and user privacy:

This site’s compliance with the above legislation, all of which are stringent in nature, means that this site is likely compliant with the data protection and user privacy legislation set out by many other countries and territories as well. If you are unsure about whether this site is compliant with your own country of residences’ specific data protection and user privacy legislation you should contact our data protection officer (details of whom can be found below) for clarification.

##  Personal information that this website collects and why we collect it

This website collects and uses personal information for the following reasons:

###  Site visitation tracking

Like most websites, this site uses Google Analytics (GA) to track user interaction. We use this data to determine the number of people using our site, to better understand how they find and use our web pages and to see their journey through the website.

Although GA records data such as your geographical location, device, internet browser and operating system, none of this information personally identifies you to us. GA also records your computer’s IP address which could be used to personally identify you but Google do not grant us access to this. We consider Google to be a third party data processor (see below).

GA makes use of cookies, details of which can be found on [Google’s developer guides.](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage) FYI our website uses the analytics.js implementation of GA.

Disabling cookies on your internet browser will stop GA from tracking any part of your visit to pages within this website.

###  **Cookie and Privacy**

_What is a cookie?_

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

Find out more about cookies:

[Information Comissioner's Office guidance on cookie regulations (PDF)](https://ico.org.uk/media/for-organisations/documents/1545/cookies_guidance.pdf)

Cookie |  Name |  Purpose |  Further information  
---|---|---|---  
Cookies set by Drupal |  has_js  
SESS... | 

The has_js cookie records whether your browser has JavaScript enabled.

The SESS... cookie is a Drupal session cookie used when an authorised user (in other words, an EIN member) logs in. You won't get this if you are an anonymous user.

Google Analytics |  _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz | 

This website uses Google Analytics, a tool which uses cookies to provide us with information on how people use the One Young World site. This information helps us to analyse the performance of the site so we can make improvements.

These cookies don't collect information that identifies individual visitors to the website. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and is therefore anonymous. Google Analytics privacy overview

YouTube cookies |  PREF  
YSC  
VISITOR_INFO_LIVE  
ACTIVITY | 

This cookie is set by the YouTube video service on pages with embedded YouTube video.

We embed videos from our official YouTube channels using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. YouTube's privacy enhanced mode for embedded videos

Cookies set by Twitter |  __utma  
__utmc  
__utmz  
_twitter_sess  
eu_cn  
guest_id  
original_referer  
pid |  These cookies are created by Twitter. In this case they are present because a Twitter widget or button is being used on the One Young World website. |  [Twitter's privacy policy](http://twitter.com/privacy)  
Cookies set by Facebook |  Datr  
lsd  
reg_ext_ref  
reg_fb_gate  
reg_fb_ref |  These cookies, provided by Facebook, are set when a visitor is logged in to or otherwise using their service. This allows a user to easily comment or share an article with their peers through the social network. |  [Facebook's Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=115180708570932#How-does-Facebook-use-cookies%3Cbr%20/%3E)  
Ripple Platform |  RPL  
__rpl_session |    |     
  
###  **How to control or delete these cookies**

If you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by our website, you can do this through your browser settings. The [About Cookies website ](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)contains step-by-step guides to controlling or deleting cookies on a wide variety of browsers.

For information on how to control or remove cookies on your mobile phone or other devices, please refer to the device's manual or manufacturer's website.

To opt-out of third-parties collecting any data regarding your interaction on our website, please refer to their websites for further information. 

###  **Our website content (Thought Leadership & News)**

Should you choose to add a comment to any posts that we have published on our website, the name and email address you enter with your comment will be saved to this website’s database, along with your computer’s IP address and the time and date that you submitted the comment. This information is only used to identify you as a contributor to the comment section of the respective article and is not passed on to any of the third party data processors detailed below. Only your name will be shown on the public-facing website although if the supplied email address is linked to a [Disqus](https://disqus.com/) account, your Disqus photo will also be displayed.

Your comment and its associated personal data will remain on this site until we see fit to either 1.) remove the comment or 2.) remove the article. Should you wish to have the comment and its associated personal data deleted, please email us at [privacy@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:privacy@oneyoungworld.com) using the email address that you commented with.

If you are under 16 years of age you **MUST** obtain parental consent before posting a comment on our blog.

**NOTE** : You should avoid entering personally identifiable information to the actual comment field of any blog post comments that you submit on this website.

###  **Contact forms and email links**

Should you choose to contact us using the contact form on our [Contact partnerships page](https://www.oneyoungworld.com/contact-partnerships), the[ homepage](https://www.oneyoungworld.com/), the[ register your interest for a scholarship page](https://www.oneyoungworld.com/register-your-interest-scholarship) or an email link from [this page](https://www.oneyoungworld.com/contact), none of the data that you supply will be passed to / be processed by any of the third party data processors.

###  **Profiles**

If you attend the One Young World Summit as a delegate we require from you to fill out a profile (more details below).

###  Email newsletter

If you choose to join our email newsletter, the email address that you submit to us will be forwarded to Campaign Monitor who provide us with email marketing services. We consider [Campaign Monitor](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/) to be a third party data processor (see below). The email address that you submit will not be stored within this website’s own database or in any of our internal computer systems.

Your email address will remain within Campaign Monitor’s database for as long as we continue to use Campaign Monitor’s services for email marketing or until you specifically request removal from the list. You can do this by unsubscribing using the unsubscribe links contained in any email newsletters that we send you or by requesting removal via email. When requesting removal via email, please send your email to us using the email account that is subscribed to the mailing list.

If you are under 16 years of age you **MUST** obtain parental consent before joining our email newsletter.

While your email address remains within the Campaign Monitor database, you will receive periodic (approximately once a month) newsletter-style emails from us.

##  How we store your personal information

As detailed above, if you submit a comment to a post published on this website some personal information will be stored within this website’s database.

Additionally if you fill in a form for one or more of our [opportunities](https://www.oneyoungworld.com/opportunities) or one or more of our [scholarships](https://www.oneyoungworld.com/scholarships), the data you provide in each of these forms will be stored in our database.

When you register to attend the One Young World Summit, the data you provide will be stored in our database. This data is currently stored in an identifiable fashion; a limitation of the content management system that this website is build on (Drupal). In the near future we aim to use encryption to store personal data.

###  Our legal basis for processing your data

When you apply for a One Young World opportunity or scholarship, or register to attend a One Young World Summit, you enter into a contract which requires One Young World to review the content of your application/registration, contact you regarding the outcome of your application/registration and provide you with information necessary for you to take part in the activity for which you have applied. When you do this, One Young World has a lawful basis to process your personal information under Article 6(1)(b) of GDPR as the processing is necessary for One Young World to perform the contract described above.

When you attend a One Young World Summit as a delegate you become a ‘One Young World Ambassador’, this status entitles you to certain ‘Ambassador Benefits’ which include discounts for One Young World events and the right to apply for opportunities reserved for One Young World Ambassadors. One Young World has a legitimate interest in retaining the data you submit as part of your Ambassador profile in order to determine that you are eligible for Ambassador Benefits when you apply for them. If you do wish your data to be removed from the Ambassador database please send your request by email to [privacy@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:privacy@oneyoungworld.com).

When you opt-in to receive a One Young World email newsletter such as the Ambassador Newsletter, or Scholarship newsletter, One Young World relies on your consent as the lawful basis to send the newsletter that you have signed up for. You may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting [privacy@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:privacy@oneyoungworld.com) or clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link found toward the bottom of all One Young World newsletters.

###  How we use your personal information

Personal information submitted for one or more of our opportunities, scholarships or to register for a One Young World Summit will be used to determine your eligibility for the programme and to provide you with information about the programme for which you have applied.

Many opportunities and scholarships are run in collaboration with third party organisations and, when you apply for these schemes, it may sometimes be necessary for One Young World to share your information with those organisations so that partners can determine your eligibility for the programme. When it may be necessary for One Young World to share such application information it will be made explicit on the relevant application form. One Young World will never provide your personal information to a third party for marketing purposes without your explicit consent.

If you attend the One Young World Summit as a delegate, a select amount of the information you provide, will be displayed publicly on your online delegate profile which can be accessed through our [Ambassador Community Database](https://www.oneyoungworld.com/community/ambassadors). The following information will be publicly viewable on your delegate profile:

  * Your full name
  * The country that you are representing at the Summit
  * The languages you speak
  * The education history you provide
  * The organisation you say you currently work with
  * Your role within your current organisation
  * The ‘skills & expertise you indicate you possess
  * The ‘areas of interest’ you indicate on your profile.
  * Your response to the profile question ‘What are you most passionate about and engaged with and why?’
  * Your response to the profile question ‘How have you helped to create positive change in your community, country or organisation?’
  * The different links you enter in your profile (Twitter, Facebook, Website…)

If you do not wish your profile to be publicly viewable, please send your request by email to  [privacy@oneyoungworld.com.](mailto:privacy@oneyoungworld.com?subject=Make%20my%20OYW%20profile%20private)

Delegate profiles include a messaging function which enables profile holders to send messages between accounts. When you receive a profile message, our website will send you an email notification. If you do not wish to be able to send or receive profile messages unselect “Personal contact form” in your account section. You can access this section by clicking on “Settings” in the user dropdown menu in the top-right corner (or follow this [link](https://www.oneyoungworld.com/user) and click on edit settings). **You must be logged in to access your settings.**

If you attend the Summit as a delegate the information you provide in your delegate profile will be added to the One Young World Ambassador database. This information is used by the One Young World community team and the volunteers who support them to contact you about One Young World events which may be taking place in your local area, inform you of opportunities that you may be interested in and profile your work or initiatives in One Young World publications. Contact from the community team will primarily come by email but they may also phone you for time to time. If you are a One Young World Ambassador and you do not wish to be contacted by One Young World, please let us know by updating the ‘Preferences section’ of your One Young World profile.

###  Who processes your data?

As soon as you have submitted either an opportunity form, a scholarship application or created a One Young World profile, your submitted data is available for processing by One Young World staff members as well as freelancers that are hired for a specific purpose at a given time during the year. As well as One Young World staff members and freelancers, [Coordinating Ambassadors](https://www.oneyoungworld.com/coordinating-ambassadors) have also access to your data. Both freelancers and Coordinating ambassadors are limited by a written agreement in the amount of processing they are allowed to do with your data.

If you would like to have more information about the Coordinating Ambassadors and their role in the processing of data please email [info@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:info@oneyoungworld.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20and%20coordinating%20ambassadors).

##  How long are we keeping your data for?

###  Website content - Thought Leadership

The data you provide to us for a Thought Leadership article will be available on our website indefinitely (or until you ask us to remove it).

###  Ambassador Community Database

The data that you share with us in your profile will remain available until you request for it to be removed.

Note that the Visa, Hotel and Flight sections of your profile are reset after each summit.

###  Contact forms

We will keep the data you provide us in a contact form for a year starting from the date you fill out the form.

Note that if you said yes to be added to the mailing list, you will be added to our mailing list until you request to be unsubscribed; either by unsubscribing directly from the email or by sending us your request by email at [info@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:info@oneyoungworld.com?subject=Mailing%20list%20unsubscribing)

##  About this website’s server

This website is hosted by [Acquia](https://www.acquia.com/gb).

Acquia Cloud is built on Amazon Web Services (AWS) infrastructure, which is physically remote from Acquia's offices. The AWS environment consists of major regions and Availability Zones. Acquia Cloud customers may choose the geographic region for their application's location (One Young World is based in the following region: EU (Frankfurt and Ireland)).

All traffic (transferral of files) between this website and your browser is encrypted and delivered over [HTTPS](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTPS).

##  Our third party data processors

We use a number of third parties to process personal data on our behalf. These third parties have been carefully chosen and all of them comply with the legislation set out.

  * Google ([Privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/))
  * Campaign Monitor ([Privacy policy](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies/#privacy-policy))
  * Disqus ([Privacy policy)](https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy)
  * SurveyMonkey ([Privacy Policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/policy/privacy-policy/))
  * HootSuite ([Privacy Policy](https://hootsuite.com/en-gb/legal/privacy#))

##  Data Breaches

We will report any unlawful data breach of this website’s database or the database(s) of any of our third party data processors to any and all relevant persons and authorities within 72 hours of the breach if it is apparent that personal data stored in an identifiable manner has been stolen.

##  Your rights as Data Subjects

GDPR legislation ensures you have several rights in relation to how organisations process your personal information.  You can find more details about these rights [here](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/)

  1. Right to be informed
  2. Right of access
  3. Right of rectification
  4. Right to erase
  5. Right to restrict processing
  6. Right to data portability
  7. Right to object
  8. Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling

You can exercise any of these rights with respect to how One Young World uses you data at any time by contacting [privacy@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:privacy@oneyoungworld.com). You can withdraw your consent of us processing your data at any time. To do so please send your request at [privacy@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:privacy@oneyoungworld.com).

Should you wish to lodge a complaint about the way One Young World processes your data you can do so by contacting the UK Information Comissioner's Office.

##  Data Controller

The data controller of this website is: **One Young World Limited**

Whose registered office is:

14 Irving Street  
London  
WC2H 7AF

##  Data Protection Officers

Anais Nee  
Director, Digital  
Telephone: +44(0)20 3691 8061  
Email: [anais.nee@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:anais.nee@oneyoungworld.com)

Rachel Brook  
Developer, Digital  
Telephone: +44(0)20 3691 8061  
Email: [rachel.brook@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:rachel.brook@oneyoungworld.com)

Matthew Belshaw  
Community Relations Director  
Telephone: +44 (0)2036918066  
Email: [matthew.belshaw@oneyoungworld.com](mailto:matthew.belshaw@oneyoungworld.com)

##  Changes to our privacy policy

This privacy policy may change from time to time in line with legislation or industry developments. We will not explicitly inform our clients or website users of these changes. Instead, we recommend that you check this page occasionally for any policy changes. Specific policy changes and updates are mentioned in the change log below.

###  Change log

**04/01/2018**

  * Privacy policy instigated

**18/01/2018**

  * Privacy policy updated

**25/04/2018**

  * Privacy policy updated
